(忆往昔)
鲍比  鲍比
Bobby. Bobby!
右额叶区有枪伤
Gunshot wound to the right frontal area.
没有发现出口伤
No exit wound found.
你好  辛格先生  你的时辰到了
Hello, Mr. Singer. Your time's up.
小混球
Idjits.
鲍比
Bobby?
是走是留  你怎么打算
What's it gonna be? Stay or go?
你对我撒谎
You lied to me.
还杀了我的朋友
And you killed my friend.
杀死艾米可没错
Killing Amy was not wrong.
你下不了手  所以我来
You couldn't do it, so I did.
老实说吧
Tell you the truth,
我都不知道做这些事为了什么
I don't know why I'm doing much of anything anymore.
我不请自说地给你个建议  放弃吧
Here's my advice you didn't ask for -- quit.
什么
What?!
绝不可能
It's not even an option.
我不会抛下我弟弟不管
I'm not gonna walk out on my brother.
那就像我一样做
Do what I did.
强迫自己直到周末都要打起精神来
Decide to be fine until the end of the week.
只要活着就要保持微笑
Make yourself smile because you're alive
这就是你该做的
and that's your job.
下一周继续如此
And do it again the next week.
要么面带微笑  好好干
Do it right... with a smile.
要么直接退出
Or don't do it.
(如今)
芭比  是你吗
Barb, that you?
[邪恶力量 第7季第13集]
早
Morning.
那是鲍比的吗
Was that Bobby's?
没想到你还留着
I didn't know you kept that.
我自己的裂了个缝
Yeah, mine sprung a leak.
一般人会拿张...
You know, most people would just carry a --
照片什么的做留念
a photo or something for a memento.
得了吧你  我这是在向鲍比致敬
Shut up, man. I'm -- I'm honoring the guy.
懂不
All right?
这算是种疗伤法
This is, uh, grief therapy.
你不是也在借白费劲的任务疗伤吗
Kind of like you and your wild-goose chase.
-白费劲  -对啊
- Wild-goose chase? - Yeah.
两周内有四个人被谋杀
Four guys murdered in two weeks,
双手双脚被砍
hands and feet cut off.
可能是某个恋脚癖发癫了
Well, some guy with a foot fetish run amuck.
成年男性被重重掷到墙上  甚至穿墙而过
Grown men thrown so hard they went through walls.
你难道没看那条新闻吗
Did you -- did you even read the article?
没  我当时在打盹
No, I was napping.
先不说这个
Well, anyway...
你还有什么别的想法
What else you got going on?
暂时查不了迪克·罗曼了  我们最好...
Dick Roman's a dead end for now. We might as well...
-忙起来  -忙起来
- Stay busy. - Stay busy.
正是
Exactly.
是啊
Yeah.
这位死者可能不会是最后一个
The latest but probably not the last.
你们俩总是忙到这么晚吗
You guys always work this late?
加班烦死人
Ugh. Hours suck.
不过福利很不错
Yeah, but great benefits package.
-是吗  -是啊
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
-药费报销10%  -真的吗
- 10% co-pay on all drugs. - Seriously?
但也就是普通的非专利药吧
Oh, but just generic, right?
不  名牌药也行的
No, no, name brands are cool.
-没错  -那么
- Yeah. - So...
这位老兄体重多少
What's our boy here weigh?
90公斤
A buck 90.
被重重掷到墙上  身体都变形了
Thrown against a wall so hard it buckled.
从犯罪现场的血流量来看
Based on the blood flow at the crime scene,
手脚在死者还一息尚存时就被砍下来了
the hands and feet were cut off while he was still alive,
和其他死者一样
just like the others.
凶手想折磨他们
The killer wanted him to suffer.
所有死者都是男性  对吧
And all the vics were male, right?
身上都刻着和这个相同的图案
With the, uh, same kind of artwork as this?
对  一模一样
Yeah. Identical.
这几个案发现场留有凶手的DNA吗
So, uh, DNA left at any of the scenes?
全都有
All of them.
前一个案子的死者咬伤了凶手
One before this, the guy bit the attacker.
尸体送过来的时候  牙里还塞了一块肉
Still had a chunk of flesh in his teeth when he came in.
简直是送上门来的证据
That's about as good as it gets.
好吧
Right.
-找到匹配了吗  -没有
- So, we have a match? - We do not.
样本被拒
Samples were rejected.
没找到任何与之匹配的基因标记
The genetic markers don't match anything we've ever seen.
和数据库里的人都不匹配吗
Didn't match any person in the database?
不  我的意思是这不是人类的样本
No. I mean, they don't match anything human.
我得承认  这可能是跟我们
I'll admit, it could be in the general vicinity
做的活儿有那么点沾边
of the ballpark of our kind of thing.
是啊  一听说"不是人类的样本"
Yeah, uh, "Didn't match anything human"
就基本没跑了
usually seals the deal for me.
我以前从没见过这个符号
I don't know. I've never seen this symbol before.
咱们先去吃点东西
Let's get a bite to eat,
然后回旅馆上网查查
go back to the motel, haul out the laptop.
好主意
That's a great idea.
这个主意太赞了
Actually, that's a brilliant idea.
我有个别的主意
Here's my counter.
你照自己说的做
You do that,
我去卧底  混进当地人群里
I'll go undercover, go mingle amongst the locals,
看看能查出什么线索
and see what kind of clues bubble to the surface.
你要去酒吧
You're going to a bar.
简而言之就是这样
If you want to oversimplify it.
(深蓝酒吧)
晚餐加电影
Dinner and a movie.
听上是去不错
Which sounded fine...
但看的却是《人体蜈蚣》
Except the movie was "Human Centipede."
等等  你不喜欢看那种片子吗
Well, so, wait. Uh, so you had a problem with that?
那是我最差劲的一次约会
The date from hell.
约会什么的最没谱了
Dating, right? Ugh.
但貌似也没别的选择
But what's the option?
我可没打算这么快就安定下来
I don't see settling down anytime soon.
很少听到有人这么说
Well, that's something you don't hear every day.
怎么
Oh, what?
你准备好走进爱情坟墓了吗
Are you ready for the big commit?
我
Me?
没有
Not exactly.
西服很帅气
Nice suit, by the way.
很多男人都不懂得打扮
Guys don't dress up much.
我喜欢
I like it.
我工作上的着装要求比较保守罢了
Yeah, well, it's, uh, a conservative line of work.
你在哪里工作
What line is that?
投资银行
Investment banking.
-老天啊  -谢谢
- Oh, god. - Thanks.
听说经常加班加点
I hear the hours are ridic.
是啊
Yeah.
不过来钱很快
But there's money to be made.
我去年挣得还不少
I've had a fortunate year.
那么
Well...
祝你财源滚滚
...may you have many more.
多谢
Arigatou.
你还会说日语吗
You speak Japanese?
皮毛而已
Ah, enough to get by.
-你真有两下子  -谁说不是呢
- Look at you. - Yeah, look at me.
那么
So...
你想换个地方接着聊吗
You want to move this conversation elsewhere?
你好  有何贵干
Hi, what can I do for you?
你脸色真差
You look like crap.
我感觉上更差
Yeah, well, I feel worse than I look.
不过我真心推荐深蓝酒吧
I do recommend the Cobalt Room, by the way.
昨晚玩得很嗨
Awesome night.
不过我这把年纪有点玩不起了
Although I think I'm getting too old for this.
你研究出那个符号的含义了吗
Did you, uh, figure out that symbol?
没有  咱们得找专家帮忙
No. Um, we're gonna need an expert.
专家  咱们的专家死了
Expert? Our expert's dead.
进去吧
All right.
从墙上摔到这里
Comes off the wall down here...
布置得不错
Well, nice decor.
像是早期的屠宰场
Very early slaughterhouse.
联调局来人了
FBI.
二位  这位是夏琳·佩恩
Guys, this is Charlene Penn.
她是本案的负责人
She's the lead on the case.
案情和之前相似  没有强行闯入迹象
More of the same. Uh, no forced entry.
死者在屋内遭到抛掷
Thrown across the room.
凶手就是要折磨死者
Made to suffer.
双手双脚都被砍掉了
Both hands and feet cut off.
胸口有同样的符号
Same symbol in the chest.
不管是谁干的  这家伙真是个禽兽
Mm. Whoever the killer is, the guy's a monster.
先走了
Excuse me.
这人和上一个很相似
This guy's just like the last one.
30出头  长相英俊
Eerly 30s, decent looking?
对  和之前三个也差不多
Yeah. Just like the first three, you know?
事业有成  并没有什么敌人
Fairly successful, no known enemies.
过来看
Here.
打扰下
Excuse me.
我来处理吧
I got it.
你有什么事
How can I help you?
我只是想弄清楚这是怎么回事
I was just trying to find out what happened.
杰瑞是我朋友
Jerry was a friend.
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
昨晚杰瑞被谋杀了
Jerry was killed sometime last night.
你住附近吗
Do you live nearby?
对  隔了两间屋
Yeah. Two doors down.
你知道会有人想伤害杰瑞吗
You, uh, you know anyone who would want to harm Jerry?
没有  他可是个大好人
No. He was the nicest guy in the world.
但他妻子和他关系挺紧张的
Well, his -- his wife wasn't real happy with him.
为什么
Why's that?
几天前  他有过一夜情
A few nights ago, he has a little one-night fling.
安发现了  之后离开了
Ann found out, took off.
但她绝不会做出这种事
But...she would never do anything like...
是啊  当然不会
Yeah. Of course.
谢谢
Thanks.
那是谁
Who was that?
邻居
Neighbor.
他说死者的妻子发现他出轨了
Said the vic's wife caught him cheating.
对  但是总不会是他妻子干的
Yeah, but we're not thinking it's the wife.
除非她能举起350磅的东西
Not unless she benches 350
并且杀掉其他那几个人作为热身
and did the other guys as a warm-up.
见鬼
Shoot.
我把鲍比的酒瓶落在莉迪亚那了
I left Bobby's flask over at Lydia's.
莉迪亚是谁
Lydia?
我昨晚的锻炼搭档
My workout partner from last night.
现在我得过去取一下
Now I've got to go get it.
那么你不但知道她的名字
So, not only do you know her name,
你还要打电话给她吗
you're actually gonna call her?
去死吧
Bite me.
太好了  她把电话给你了
Sweet -- she gave you her number.
她们都会给你留电话
They always give you their number.
喂
Hello?
莉迪亚
Lydia.
是我  昨晚的迪恩
Hey, it's, uh, Dean from last night.
我想我好想落了点东西在你那儿
Uh, listen, I think I left something over at your place.
是一个旧的酒瓶
It was an old flask.
看起来可能不起眼  但它有些纪念意义
It doesn't look like much, but it has sentimental value.
你看见了吗
So, uh, have you seen it?
没有
No.
但如果我看见了  我会打给你的
But if I do, I'll call.
我要我的电话号码吗
You want my number?
我手机会自动存下来的
My cell grabbed it.
抱歉
Uh...sorry.
我得先挂了
I gotta go.
这会儿有点忙
Just real busy at the moment.
她真的很忙
She's real busy.
呼吸
Breath.
控制住  莉迪亚
Control, Lydia,
所有的事情都应该如此
as in all things.
最后一次用力
One final push.
这疼痛是一种荣誉
The pain is an honor.
我们给她起个什么名字呢
What will we call her?
你就叫她艾玛吧
You'll call her Emma.
下一个
Next.
(人类学系)
有意思
Fascinating,
真的
truly.
事实上  这符号画得不错
And actually, rather accomplished draftsmanship.
对  如果不去想
Yeah, if you get past the fact
它是刻在人身上的话
that it was carved into a guy's body.
莫瑞森教授
Professor Morrison,
我们希望你能告诉我们这符号什么意思
we're hoping you can tell us what the symbol means.
好  也许能
Yeah, maybe.
也许能
Maybe?
我很有可能可以
It's possible I could, even likely.
联调局有什么报酬吗
Is the FBI offering suitable remuneration?
国家会为此感激  尊敬你
The respect of a grateful nation.
我还会在国税局那儿给你说好话
And a good word with the I.R.S.
这看起来很古老
Well, it appears quite ancient.
缩小些范围
Well, that narrows it down.
这是一个和崇拜相关的符号被讹传的版本
A corrupted version of symbology associated with worship.
肯定是哪个地区的含糊的手绘版本
Definitely an obscure regional script.
这得研究些时日
Oh, this will require some research.
太好了
All right. Great.
我想我们明天再来找你
Well, uh, I guess we'll be seeing you tomorrow.
明天
Tomorrow?!
我曾经放弃假期研究这样的项目
I've spent entire sabbaticals on a project like this.
教授
Professor!
我们在追查一个连环杀手
We have a serial killer on our hands.
你的政府需要你  先生
Your government needs you, sir.
先生们
Gentlemen,
我的管家需要一张绿卡
my housekeeper needs a green card.
天啊  你在哪找到的这家伙
Good god, where'd you find this guy?
他可是这领域最权威的专业人士
He's supposed to be a top expert in his field.
是啊  但如果他研究领域的东西
Yeah, well, when his field includes things
会在夜里捣鬼
that go bump in the night,
他最好值得咱们刚才浪费的口舌
he's gonna be worth the breath we just wasted.
那咱们应该怎么办呢  迪恩
So, what are we supposed to do, Dean?
浪费时间吗
Spin our wheels?
萨姆  这就是浪费时间  好吧
Sam, this is us spinning our wheels, okay?!
迪恩  我也想找他  好吗
Dean, you know what? I want to call him, too, okay?
相信我
Believe me.
但鲍比不在了
But Bobby's not here.
所以我们只能将就了
So we're settling.
好吧
Yeah.
只能这样了
We sure are.
见鬼  她怎么还不打电话
Damn it, why hasn't she called?
谁  莉迪亚吗
Who? Lydia?
等等  难道这次是你被一个姑娘给玩了
Wait, so some girl's actually dumping you the morning after?
我觉得你的幸灾乐祸有点过了
I think you're enjoying this a little more than you need to.
不管她了  我过去取那酒瓶
Screw it. I'm going over there and getting the flask.
唐
Don.
是迪恩
Dean.
我猜你是没收到我的短信
I guess you didn't get my messages.
不  我收到了  我一直很忙
No, I did. I've been busy.
那晚我把我的酒瓶落在这了
Anyway, I, uh, left that flask over here the other night.
对  我找到了
Yes. I found it.
它真的很旧很烂  我差点扔了
It was so beat up and old, I almost tossed it.
对  它的主人也是一个德行
Yeah, well, guy it belonged to was beat up and old, too.
但我和他关系很好
But I was very close with him,
我不想丢了他的酒瓶
and I'd, uh, I'd hate to lose it.
我给你拿
I'll get it for you.
你怎么样啊
So, how you been?
除了很忙以外
Other than "Busy."
就那样
Just that.
真的很忙  给你
Really busy. Here you go.
哦  天啊
Oh, wow.
能看出来你很忙  你在帮人照看孩子啊
I can see why you're busy. You've been babysitting, huh?
不是
No.
她是你的孩子吗
Yours?
你没告诉我你还有个小女儿
You didn't tell me you had a little girl.
我们大概还有很多没对彼此坦白的事呢
There's probably all kinds of things we didn't tell each other.
她叫什么
What's her name?
艾玛
Emma.
你好啊  艾玛  这是你的第一个孩子吗
Hi, Emma. Your first?
对
Yes.
我听说她们这年龄长得很快
Well, I hear they grow like weeds.
你根本想象不到
You have no idea.
抱歉  我得接这电话
Sorry. I got to take this.
喂
Hello.
你人呢
Mm. Hey. Where are you?
只是个酒瓶啊  又不是圣杯
It's a flask, not the holy grail.
伙计  我这人喜欢与人打交道
Hey, man, I'm a people person, all right?
我正忙着交际呢
I'm engaging in some social skills.
莫瑞森给你回话了吗
You get anything out of Morrison?
还没有  你能回来吗
No. Not yet. Look, would you get back here?
罪证化验室那边让咱们过去
We're due at the crime lab.
迪恩
Dean?
等等
Hang on.
你要不...
Hey, look, why don't you just...
那间屋里的人是谁啊
Who's that guy in the other room?
那是谁
Who is that?
你还在吗
You there?
别出声  等下再说
Don't talk. We'll discuss it later.
喂
Hello!
我等下打给你
I'll call you back.
死者依然是体重不轻
So, again, we got a guy weighing about two bills...
却被猛力扔到墙上
Thrown into a wall so hard,
以致颅骨中都插入几片石膏
he's got pieces of plaster lodged in his skull.
联邦探员为什么也来掺和这案子
What triggered the feds' involvement in this case?
我总以为你们另有要事
I always think you boys have bigger fish to fry.
不是这样  实际上  我们
No. Actually, we...
我想是因为跟之前几桩悬案很相似吧
I just figured it was the similarity to the other cold cases?
如果是同一凶手所为
If it's the same killer,
那他必然跨越了州界线  所以你们来了
then he crossed state lines -- that would bring you guys in.
没错
Well, that's exactly right.
如他所说
Uh, what he said.
好吧  随你吧
Yeah. Whatever,
你得搞定这事
you're gonna have to wrap this up.
我们手里的案子不止你这件
Your case isn't the only one we're working on.
习惯就好了
You get used to her.
艾迪  对了
Uh, so, Eddie, by the way,
我没带那些悬案的资料
I didn't bring the cold-case files with me.
你有副本吗
Is there a chance you have a copy?
-当然  -好极了
- Yeah. - Great.
深蓝酒吧
The Cobalt Room.
是的  它名气很大
Yeah, it's pretty well known.
要找艳遇的话  那地方不错
Looking to hook up, it's a pretty good place to go.
我听说过
I've heard.
二号死者也去过
Vic Number Two was there.
据保安人员说
And according to his security guard,
他跟一个漂亮姑娘走了
he left with a hot girl.
两天后  他就死了
Two days later, he's an obituary.
和杰瑞·普莱斯情况一样
Same with Jerry Price.
没错  而且就我们看来
Mm-hmm. And, uh, as far as we can tell,
有多起相似案件
at least a couple of those in there.
与芝加哥的案件如出一辙
Same thing in Chicago.
是的  多数死者婚姻破裂
Yep. A lot of busted marriages,
或是跟陌生女人有一夜情  如此之类的
flings with unknown women, that kind of thing.
都是在他们死前
All just before they got offed.
多谢
Thanks.
艾玛准备好了吗
Is Emma ready?
是的  进来吧
Yes. Come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
-喂  -伙计
- Yeah. - Dude.
你怎么没来
You never showed.
我在莉迪亚家外面
I'm outside Lydia's.
拜托  老兄  你怎么  你迷上她了吗
Oh, come on, man. What, are you obsessed or something?
不  听我说
No, I'm telling you.
我下午目睹了好多怪事
I have been eating at the buffet of strange all afternoon.
什么意思
Meaning what?
等我弄清楚就告诉你
I'll tell you the second I know.
事情不大对劲
But something ain't right.
或是你迷上她了
Or you're obsessed.
闭嘴  我是说真的
Shut up. I'm serious.
好吧  你需要后援还是
Okay, uh, you need backup or...
不  还不用  你那边情况怎样
No, not yet. What's up on your end?
看来  同样的连环谋杀以前也有
Apparently, there was an identical murder fest
两年前在芝加哥  再两年前
two years years ago in Chicago, and again in Miami
迈阿密也有
two years before that.
所有死者都是年轻的成功人士
All the victims were young, successful,
许多人去过同一间酒吧
a lot of them went to the same bar.
好几起案子  总是很快就断了线索
It lines up. The trails always went cold fast.
-是吗  -是的  顺便提下
- Yeah? - Yeah. Oh, and by the way...
我得私下提醒你
As a personal kicker,
在这边  至少部分死者
here, at least some of the vics
都在你去的酒吧泡过女人
hooked up in that bar you went to,
就是  那间"深蓝酒吧"
The, uh, The Cobalt Room.
所以  伙计  你躲过一劫了
So, just saying, man, you, you dodged the bullet.
我得挂了
Got to go.
聊天愉快
Nice talk.
艾玛  快点
Emma, hurry up.
快来  艾玛  要走了
Come on, Emma. Time to go.
艾玛
Emma.
做个好女孩
You be a good girl.
让我们为你骄傲
Make us proud.
我会的  妈妈
I will, mommy.
再见 艾玛
Bye, Emma.
我真讨厌这种事
I hate when this happens.
那又如何
So what?
也许她还有一个孩子  只是没告诉你
I mean, so maybe she has another kid she didn't tell you about.
不会  就这一个
Nope, just the one.
是艾玛
Emma.
但那晚我和她在一起时
But that night, when I was with her,
她还没有孩子
she didn't have any.
我去过她家  伙计
And I was at her place, man.
那里没有游戏围栏  毯子或者橡皮鸭
There was no playpens, no blankets, no rubber ducks.
行了  说得好像你真能观察那么细
Right. Like you would have been focused on that kind of thing.
老弟  这是你观察到的第一件事
Hey, dude, that's the first thing you notice.
那是危险警报
Red flags.
然后  突然之间  嘭
Then, all of a sudden, boom --
孩子出现了
baby.
就是你看到说话的那个
Yeah, the one you thought talked.
她的确说话了
Oh, it talked.
还不是婴儿嘟嘟囔囔那种
And not baby talk, either.
你什么时候这么了解儿童发育了
Now you know so much about child development?
至少我知道他们不该会说
I know enough to know that they don't say,
"妈妈  那个家伙是谁"
"Hey, mom. Who's that guy?"
言归正传
So, cut to...
莉迪亚把那个叫她妈妈的小孩
Lydia's handing this kid who's calling her mommy
交给两个女人
over to these two women, right?
但这次不是婴儿了
But this is not a baby.
不是  绝对不是  这小孩得有五岁
No, no, this kid's got to be 5...
名字还是艾玛
And same name -- Emma.
乔治·福尔曼(世界重量级拳击冠军)给所有儿子都命名乔治
You know, George Foreman named all his sons george.
你故意惹我是吧
Are you deliberately messing with me?
老弟  我知道什么事不对劲
Dude, I know weird.
好吗  这事情怎么说都不对劲
Okay? There is no non-weird explanation for this.
今早  艾玛还是个婴儿
This morning, Emma was a baby.
傍晚她就摇身变成汉娜·蒙塔纳
By sunset, she's Hannah Montana.
早年的她
Early years.
是教授
It's the professor.
太好了  是教授
Oh. Good. The professor. Yeah.
-我确信他能解开谜题  -嘘
- I'm sure he'll crack this wide open. - Shh!
在这个特殊晚上
On this special night,
你们将加入一个特别的家族
you join an exceptional family.
你们已准备好在我们中取得一席之位
You are ready to take your places alongside us,
并学习我们的传统
and learn our traditions.
这是向我们的创造者也是保护者致敬
This is a tribute to the one who created and protects us.
我们为她狩猎
We hunt for her.
为她杀戮
We kill for her.
现在我们将猎物吃下  以表示我们的团结
And now we consume that kill as a symbol of unity,
与那些已经完成了他们血的使命的人融为一体
with those who have completed their blood missions,
也延续我们部落的血脉
and furthered the life of the tribe.
吃啊  艾玛  你要吃了它
Go ahead, Emma. You need to eat.
要知道  辨认出这个符号
You know, identifying this scroll
可不是轻松的事
was no day at the beach.
次级的学者只能抓狂
Lesser scholars would have crumbled.
教授  能讲讲符号吗
Professor... the symbol?
当然  当然
Yeah. Yeah.
它很古老  地域性强
It's ancient, regional.
非常难鉴别
Very difficult to identify.
但我终于找到了匹配的符号
But I managed to find a match.
它是一个符号的变形
It's a variation of a symbol
与希腊万神殿有关
associated with the Greek Pantheon,
是女神哈耳摩尼亚(和谐与协调女神)的神庙
the temple of the Goddess Harmonia.
根据神话
According to myth,
哈耳摩尼亚与战神阿瑞斯结合
the coupling of Harmonia and Ares, the god of war,
创造了亚马逊人
produced the Amazons.
亚马逊人
The Amazons?
是神奇女侠那种吗
Like Wonder Woman?
不  是一个战士组成的部落
No, like -- like a tribe of warriors.
他们真实存在过
They actually existed.
漫画都是些愚蠢的曲解
The comic books -- they're just silly perversions.
我认为这个符号起源于亚马逊人的符号
The symbol -- I believe it originated with the Amazons,
是用来向哈耳摩尼亚致敬的象形文字
pictographs meant to pay homage to Harmonia --
你可以叫它神秘附身符
occult talismans, if you will.
他们格外崇尚女性文化
They had an exclusively female culture.
男性完全是没用的  除了繁衍后代
No use for men whatsoever, except procreation.
所有死者都是男性
All the vics were male.
就像你说的  这个符号
So you said -- with this symbol
被刻在他们胸前
carved in their chests.
手脚都被砍掉了
And their hands and feet cut off.
瞧  亮点就在这里
Now, that is interesting.
引起了我们的注意
Got our attention.
她们怀孕后
After they were impregnated,
就会杀了男人
they killed the male --
但先要砍掉特定的身体部位
First cutting off certain body parts.
我没法查到他们的身份
I couldn't check their I.Ds.
因为他们所有文件都是伪造的
Because everything they have is fake.
我查了好久了
I've been digging for hours.
只有一点是确定的  他们不是联邦调查局的
And one thing's for sure -- they ain't FBI.
那他们是谁
And who are they?
他们是来追查我们的
They're after us, is what they are.
还记得之前穿越全国的大屠杀吗
Remember that cross-country murder spree?
几个月前那对疯狂的兄弟
Those crazy brothers went on a couple months ago?
-是他们吗  -还只是冰山一角
- That's them? - Barely scratches the surface.
他们是暴徒
They're thugs.
侠士
Vigilantes.
但是  听着  我们以前也和这样的猎人交过手
But, look, we've dealt with hunters like this before.
这样嘛...
Well...
其中一个已经计划好要除掉了
The one is already scheduled to be taken care of.
再把另一个也安排在日程上就行了
We'll just simply add the other one to the agenda.
我知道鲍比有本专讲希腊怪事的书
I know Bobby's got a Grecian encyclopedia of weird in here.
我还看见过呢  就是翻这堆该死的...
I saw it last time I was looking through this stupid...
按序摆放会要他命吗
Would it kill him to have a system?
他有顺序
He has a system.
他的资料像他的大脑一样井然有序
His files are set up like his brain.
有发现吗
You got anything?
有
Uh, yeah.
有一堆关于亚马逊人的疯狂传说
There's this whole crazy side to Amazon lore
那个莫瑞森教授没提到呢
that professor Morrison didn't even mention.
那是因为他不相信那些
That's 'cause he doesn't believe in it,
而我们想要对付他们  他的态度就很碍事了
which is a real handicap when you're trying to deal with it.
没错
Right.
看来曾经发生过漫长而血腥的战争
Um, apparently, there was this long, bloody war.
亚马逊人口骤减
The Amazon population was decimated,
所以他们和哈耳摩尼亚达成协议
so they made a bargain with Harmonia
增加人口数目和增强人口体格
to replenish their ranks and make them stronger.
要我说能把成年男人扔穿墙  体格是大大增强了
Well, I'd say throwing grown men through walls was stronger.
没错  总的来说他们比人类强壮多了
Yeah. Well, basically, they became more than human.
哈耳摩尼亚把他们都变成怪物了
Harmonia turned them into monsters.
他们能和人一样被杀死吗
Can you kill them like humans?
还是需要什么技巧
Or is there some kind of trick?
没提到
Uh doesn't say.
不知道  我想大概都有可能
No idea. I guess it could go either way.
很有用  还有呢
Well, that's helpful. What else?
传说是他们繁殖非常快
The lore says they reproduced quickly --
快到  男女结合后36小时她们就能生产
as in, after mating, they gave birth within 36 hours.
孩子生长也异常快速
The babies grew incredibly fast,
然后生长速度就会变得正常
then the aging process became normal.
我想  这也是组建军队的一种办法
Which is one way to make an army, I guess.
结合周期大约是两年
The mating cycle is every two years.
他们会把所有达到生育年龄的妇女派出去
They send out all the women who have reached child-bearing age.
这就说得通了  因为每两年才会换个城市
Which lines up, 'cause this happens every couple of years
发生一次  对吗
in different towns, right?
对
Yeah.
我们明确知道至少有数名死者
And we know for sure that at least some of the vics
曾经和陌生女子在一起
hooked up with strange women
之后就被以亚马逊人的方式杀掉了
days before being killed Amazon style.
是在我泡到莉迪亚的酒吧把到妹子的吗
Hooked up in the same bar I met Lydia, right?
-是啊  -然后突然之间
-Yeah. - And then suddenly,
她就迅速有了个孩子
she's got a little baby in like fruit-fly time.
小宝宝很快变成了小女孩
That baby turns into a little girl just as fast.
-所以也许你是  -别说了
- So maybe you're -- - Don't say it.
听着  如果那孩子是你的
Look, if that kid's yours --
我说了别说了
I said don't say it!
好吧  不说了  但是  迪恩
Fine. I won't. But, Dean...
兄弟  说真的  一夜情  你就打算...
Dude, seriously, a one-night stand, you're just gonna...
-碰运气吗  你连那个都...  -当然不是
- roll the dice? You don't even -- - Of course not...
萨姆
Sam.
你以为我傻啊
What, do you think I'm brain-dead?
总是有意外的
Accidents happen.
就算是发生了意外
If one even did,
而且我觉得不是这样的...
which I-I-I don't think...
不  你知道吗  不说了
No. You know what? Stop.
我们不要再说这件事了
We're not gonna talk about this anymore
我都起鸡皮疙瘩了
because my skin's starting to crawl!
那好吧
All right, fine.
但如果是真的  如果发生了这种事
But if it's true, if it happened...
我知道  我得小心我的手和脚
I know. I got to hang on to my hands and feet.
你们的进步让我们十分欣慰
We are so pleased with your progress.
你们在汲取我们先母的传统
You are absorbing the traditions of our mothers,
你们即将完成你们的部落使命
and you are close to fulfilling your tribal destiny,
与你们的姐妹并肩作战
and taking your place alongse your sisters.
今天  你们成为战士
Today, you are a warrior.
你们虽与他人同行
Though you may walk among others,
却要心属部落
your heart is only with the tribe.
很快  你们就要迈出最终的光荣的一步长大成人
Soon, you will take the final, glorious step into adulthood.
今天你们要学会如何忍受痛苦
Today, you will learn how to endure pain
以及如何给他人痛苦
and how to inflict it.
顶住  艾玛
Fight it, Emma.
凡事皆须如此
As with all you do,
勇气是你的全部
courage is everything.
看鲍比的资料真是垃圾里捞针
Looking through Bobby's files is like dumpster diving.
可不是嘛
Yeah, tell me about it.
亚马逊人想找
So, it makes sense why the Amazons
高帅富结合也说得通
all want to hook up with decent-looking, successful guys.
传宗接代还挑三拣四吗
Oh, they're picky about the gene pool?
是啊
Right.
那么...
So...
莉迪亚干嘛选了你
What was Lydia doing with you?
她可能或许以为我是富有的投资银行家
Well, she may or may not have thought I was a rich investment banker.
萨姆
Sam.
怎么了
Yeah.
这几张纸动地方了
These papers just moved.
-啥  -我可没动
- What? - I didn't touch them.
到处都是
It's all over the place.
红的
Redline.
对了
Oh, and...
电力线就在敞开的窗子旁边
power lines by the open window,
刚好有阵小风
where there's a breeze...
-可能吹动了纸  -你感到小风了吗
- That could have moved the papers. - Did you feel a breeze?
那也没什么关系了  迪恩  读数是无效的
It doesn't matter, Dean. The readings are useless.
有可能是...
Maybe, uh...
我们把他火葬了  迪恩
We burned him, Dean.
-那又如何  -你是什么意思
- So what? - So, what are you suggesting?
不知道  你呢
I don't know. What are you?
专心干别的吧
Concentrate on something else.
-为什么  -因为那不是鲍比
- Why? - Because it's not Bobby!
-有可能啊  -不  不可能
- Could be. - No, it couldn't be.
-为什么  -因为那是我们一厢情愿
- Why not? - Because we want it to be.
或许会有用
Maybe it's useful.
这一堆的东西都"或许有用"
It's in a pile of "Maybe it's useful."
再说  这是希腊文  没人会读希腊文
Besides, it's in Greek. Nobody reads greek.
是啊  除了希腊人
Yeah, except Greeks.
还有鲍比
Oh, and Bobby.
还有莫瑞森教授
And professor Morrison.
不是吧
Really?
我要去找他  迪恩
I'm going, Dean.
待在这儿  锁好门
You stay here, keep the door locked.
哪都别去
Don't go anywhere.
-不开玩笑  -好吧
- I mean it. - Fine.
你不是吧
Oh, you have got to be kidding.
我明天有办公时间
I have office hours tomorrow --
抱歉  教授  我需要你帮忙
I'm sorry, professor. I need your help.
联调局给我的酬劳不够
The FBI isn't paying me enough for this.
好吧  我再给你点好处
All right. I'll sweeten the deal.
我们不监听你了
We'll remove your wiretap.
你不认识我  我叫艾玛
You don't know me, but my name is Emma.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我想我有麻烦了
I think I'm in trouble,
而你是我唯一能够信任的人
and you're the only person I can trust.
为什么
Why?
因为你是我父亲
Because you're my father.
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
他们一直在监视你
They've been watching you,
从妈妈怀孕就开始了
ever since mom got pregnant.
如果你真的被囚禁了
Well, if you're such a prisoner,
能告诉我你怎么跑出来的吗
you mind telling me how you escaped?
我等到熄灯
I waited until lights out.
看着我们的女人十点过一点时换班
The women who watch over us change shifts a little after 10:00.
那你为什么离开
And you left because...?
他们把你安排在那儿
They stick you in there,
你就信任他们
and you trust them.
根本不知道别的
It's all you know.
你也不去质疑他们要你做的事
And you don't question what they want you to do --
那些可怕的事
terrible things.
所以我必须离开
That's why I had to leave.
他们折磨我
They tortured me.
他们告诉我说我必须忍受痛苦
They told me I had to endure pain
那样才能像他们一样强壮
so I could be strong like them.
但我不想像他们一样
But I don't want to be like them.
好吧
Okay.
进来
Come on in.
坐下
Have a seat.
好吧
Okay.
那我们假设你...不像他们
Let's assume that you're not... like them.
暂时不像
Yet.
你想要我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
带我离开这里
Get me away from here.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
我妈妈告诉我了
My mother told me that.
我十分怀疑她会说这话
I seriously doubt she said that.
如果你了解我  也会十分质疑这句话的真实性
And if you knew me, you would seriously doubt it's true.
他们告诉我你是个猎人
They told me you're a hunter.
那么或许你能理解我
So maybe you'll understand about me.
或许你能保护我
Maybe you can protect me.
只要让我能逃离他们就行
Just long enough so I can get away.
然后我就不来烦你了
Then I'll leave you alone.
我知道你不想要我
I know you don't want me.
好了  咱们...不说那个  行吗
All right, let's not...go there, okay?
这根本不是...
This isn't a matter of...
你能明白这个情况很不寻常吧
You get this isn't a normal situation, right?
我要怎么明白
How would I know?
我三天前还不存在呢
Three days ago, I wasn't even alive.
而我现在就在这儿
Now here I am.
我妈妈把我扔进那里
My mother threw me into that place.
而我爸爸...
And my father...
就不说了...
...well...
你知道这是我过上一点正常生活的最后机会了吧
You get this is my last chance to have anything normal ever, right?
真令人着迷
It's fascinating.
上面怎么说
What's it say?
我还没看呢
Oh, I haven't gotten there yet.
这纸张是手工制作的
The paper is handmade.
用纤维素  很像纸莎草纸
A cellulose, rather like papyrus,
所以它能长时间保存
which would explain its durability.
-教授  -你是怎么拿到的
- Professor - - Wherever did you get it?
一个天才的老疯子酒鬼给我的
A crazy, drunk, old genius.
是啊  他们总是有些好东西
Yeah. They always have the good stuff.
是用希腊文写的
Well, it's in greek.
对  对  这我知道
Yeah, yeah. I-I know that.
可不是什么普通的方言
Not a common dialect.
我的天  你怎么就跟亚马逊人干上了
My god, what is it with you and Amazons?
教授  这是要紧事
Professor, it's important.
晚上11点半来找我  最好是要紧事
At 11:30 at night, it better be.
这有个新的大逆转
Oh, here's a new twist.
这上面的叙述和常见传说相同
It repeats the conventional lore.
亚马逊的战士与男子结合  男子被杀
Amazon warriors mate with males. The males are murdered.
之类的  但是这上面说...
Yada, yada. But according to this...
杀人的不是女人
it's not the women who do the killing.
作为入门仪式的一部分
Instead, a ritual of initiation
要求男女结合而生下的孩子
requires that the child born of the mating process
必须要杀掉她的父亲
must kill her own father.
什么
What?
你好像很累
You look exhausted.
还很饿呢
And starving?
我的花季很艰辛
It's been a tough sweet 16.
你相信我了吗
So you believe me?
你会帮我吗
You'll help me?
如果你是真想找人帮忙
If you really want help.
探长
Detective.
探员  这么晚还来这儿
Agent. You're here late.
是啊  是这样  我们能不能早上再说
Yeah. Listen, could we talk in the morning?
你急什么...
What's your hurry...
萨姆
...Sam?
萨姆·温彻斯特  我想想
Sam Winchester. Let's see.
我可以以假扮联邦探员的罪名带你回去
I could run you in for impersonating a federal agent.
如果他们发现你失踪了会怎么样
Well, now, what happens when they find out you're missing?
他们大概已经发现了
They may have already found out.
他们会找到我
And they'll hunt me down.
听着  我知道这肯定不容易
Look, I know this is gonna be hard,
但如果我想逃出去  就必须现在逃
but if I'm gonna get out, I have to do it now.
我这儿有奶酪和剩下的玉米煎饼
We got cheese and a leftover burrito.
都一样的
Doesn't make a difference.
你刚刚问我相不相信你
You were asking if I believed you.
她们说了拿下你会不容易
I was told you'd be a challenge.
我就猜你会跟我闲扯
I figured you'd chat me up...
想让我放松警惕
try and catch me off guard.
差点就起效了
Almost worked.
不过我等的是你妈妈
I was expecting your mother.
这事不是由她来做
It's not her place.
我得杀了你
I have to kill you.
-她们这么跟你说的吗  -这是我的使命
- Is that what they told you? - It's what I am.
那我现在就该杀了你
Well, then, I should just kill you right now.
好啊
Sure.
但是你三十秒前就能这么做了
But you could have done that 30 seconds ago.
怪的是不好下手  是不是
It's weirdly hard, isn't it?
-我就有点于心不忍  -少来了
- It is for me. - Knock it off.
怎么能轻松呢  你是我爸爸啊
How could it not be? You're my father.
-我们少来这套  -但确实如此
- Hey! We're not gonna do that. - But it's true.
我们会走到这一步是因为你
You're the reason that we're standing here.
如果没有你  也不会有我了
I wouldn't be here if it weren't for you.
现在我们是你死我活
So now someone has to kill someone.
你知道吗
You know what?
到目前为止  我的童年真是不怎么样
So far, my childhood's been kind of disappointing.
你还没杀过人  艾玛
You haven't killed anybody yet, Emma.
放弃吧
Walk away.
现在就放弃  我不会去追杀你
Right now -- I won't go after you.
不行啊
I can't.
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
求你别让他伤害我
Please don't let him hurt me.
大本营在此
Here's the mother ship.
我们去做个了结吧
Let's get this done.
她们跑了
They're gone.
你知道吗  我也不喜欢这样
Hey, you know what? I don't like it, either.
我跟你一样  也很想折磨她们
I wanted to torture them just as much as you.
但是...
Yeah, but, hey...
下次她们再出现  我们就有所准备了
next time they surface, we'll be ready...
如果我们能活到那时候
If we live that long.
好吧  你就坐在那儿生闷气吧
All right, fine. Just sit there and be pissed.
你以前怎么跟我说的...
What did you say to me...
我下不了手的时候
when I was the one who choked?
你是怎么说艾米的
What did you say about Amy?
"是怪就得杀"
"You kill the monster!"
我的确要杀她的
I was going to!
你才不是呢  你当我二啊
Oh, the hell you were! You think I'm an idiot?
你当我二啊
What, you think I am?
迪恩  你本打算放跑她的
Dean, you were gonna let her walk!
我才没有  你别瞎说
No, I wasn't. That's ridiculous!
听着  她不是你的孩子  不是真正意义上的
Look, man, she was not yours. Not really.
其实她还真是
Actually, she, uh, she was, really.
只不过她还是个疯狂的杀男人的怪物
She just also happened to be a crazy man-killing monster.
不过呢
But, uh, hey.
知道吗  鲍比说得对
You know what? Bobby was right.
你心没在这儿
Your head's not in it, man.
小卡死的时候  你就很难过了  现在...
When Cass died, you were wobbly, but now...
现在怎么了
Now what?
你就应对得很好吗
Oh, what, you're dealing with it so perfect?
告诉你个消息
Yeah, news flash, pal --
你跟我一样一团乱
you're just as screwed up as I am!
你不过...块头大点而已
You're just...bigger.
-啥  -不知道我说了啥
- What?! - I don't know.
听着
Look...
迪恩  问题在于  今晚
Dean, the thing is, tonight...
你险些丧命
it almost got you killed.
我不管你怎么应对这件事
Now, I don't care how you deal.
我真的不管
I really, really don't.
但你别...
But just don't --
别挂掉了
don't get killed.
我尽力而为吧
I'll do what I can.
你这话什么意思
Well, what's that supposed to mean?
意思是我尽力而为  好吗
It means I'll do what I can. All right?
你就别唠叨了
You can shut up about it.